

ABOUT ME

I have three (3) years of experience analyzing industry data, market trends, and audiences in order to assist a variety teams with achieving their respective objectives.

Furthermore, I have two (2) years of experience connecting creative talent with brand in order to facilitate their marketing goals.

In these various roles, I have gained the critical thinking, organizational, and interpersonal skills necessary to excel in a diverse array of projects.

PRO SKILLS

PROJECT MANAGEMENT

CLIENT ENGAGEMENT

LEAD SOURCING & GENERATION

MEASUREMENT

RESEARCH

PERSONAL SKILLS

CREATIVITY

TEAMWORK

COMMUNICATION

LEADERSHIP

TYLER HUYSER

9 43 Ave. C, New York, NY 10009

**** 301-318-4896

www.tylerhuyser.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

VAYNERMEDIA

New York, NY 2018-Present

Analyst - Influencer Media

- Helped shape influencer strategy by analyzing industry data, markets, and audiences in order to identify prime sales targets
- Oversaw the implementation of brand campaigns (from contracting through measurement & reporting) while managing communication with both the client and influencer talent
- Collaborated with sales marketing team in order to build media plans, budgets, timelines, and concepts for RFPs & sold programs

Resident Analyst - Influencer Media

- Sourced influencers based on their relevancy to the initiative and negotiated directly with their agents & managers
- Tracked live content in order to order to ensure that all aspects were delivered upon time successfully
- Carried out quantitative and qualitative research in order to produce media evaluation reports which were used to improve the effectiveness of the campaign strategy

FIRSTBORN

New York, NY 2017

Business Development Resident

- Identified and synthesized patterns & leads, leveraging these insights for new business opportunities—ultimately leading to five (5) new deals for the agency
- Set the stage for client engagements by seamlessly orchestrating resources, processes, and conversations necessary in order to enable the studio to identify and execute on client opportunities
- Drafted dossiers of key executives & decision makers ahead of pitches with prospective clients

SHARECARE

Atlanta, GA 2016 - 2017

Assistant Project Lead - Population Health Programs

- Defined scope and created workstreams to facilitate creation of a Diabetes Prevention Program (DPP) to meet CDC requirements
- Sourced and contracted an eight-member team of clinicians to write the DPP clinical curriculum
- Performed stakeholder management of Sharecare executives,
 Healthways employees, and clinical team
- Conducted a competitive analysis of digitized population health industry - reports were used by clinical and product teams to make key decisions regarding the final product.

Business Development & Marketing Intern

 Created a database of Fortune 500 & insurance company executives for an email marketing campaign

EDUCATION

COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY •

New York, NY 2014 - 2016

Bachelors in Liberal Arts

GPA: 3.41/4.0 Major in Film Studies